jkrowling.com 2018-03-15

# Privacy & Cookies Policy - J.K. Rowling

J.K. Rowling Website Limited (the “Company”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with the Company’s terms of use and any other documents referred to on it (the “Terms and Conditions”)) sets out the basis on which any personal data and information the Company collects from you, or that you provide to the Company, will be processed by the Company during your use of [www.jkrowling.com](http://www.jkrowling.com/) (the “site”). Please read the following carefully to understand the Company’s views and practices regarding your personal data and information, how the Company will treat it and the Company’s practises with regards to use of cookies.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the data controller is J.K. Rowling Website Limited whose registered address is 89 New Bond Street, London W1S 1DA.

Please see our terms of use for more information about, and the basis on which we provide, the site.

YOUR INFORMATION

We will not collect information that personally identifies you. **We do not collect any personal data.**

COOKIES

Like many online services, the site uses a feature called a cookie, which is a small data file that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer or device’s hard drive.

The site uses cookies that automatically log certain non-personal information, including aggregated, statistical data about how you are using the site to analyse its performance and usage. This information may include the URL of the website which linked you to the site, your IP address and the number and duration of visits to the site. The IP address indicates the location of your computer on the internet. This information is collected in an anonymous way that does not identify you personally.

Various different types of cookies are used via the site:

  * “Session cookies” are used (which will usually be deleted when you log out) to keep track of your internet session, which, for instance, allows the Company to remember the site language. Without these cookies the online services that you have asked for cannot be provided. Session cookies are necessary and/or useful for the functioning of the site
  * “Persistent cookies” are used (which are longer-term) to help you move around and enjoy the features on the site more easily and to remember preferences, actions and settings to improve your visit (at your request).

The cookies outlined above expire after varying periods from around 30 minutes up to 2 years or more. The length of time that a cookie remains on your computer or mobile device depends on whether it is a “persistent” or “session” cookie. Session cookies last until you stop browsing and persistent cookies last until they expire or are deleted.

In further detail, the cookies fall into the following categories:

1 Analytics (e.g. Google Analytics; Webengage)  
These cookies are used to compile various (anonymised) metrics for our users to get a better understanding of how the site is used (pages visited and time spent on the site, for example), so that the Company can deliver more of the content you want, and less of the content you don’t. This information also helps us to make better decisions for our future initiatives. We use partners like [Webengage](http://webengage.com/privacy) and [Google Analytics](http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en-GB/policies/technologies/types/). These analytics cookies are set by those partners, and are in accordance with the relevant partner’s own privacy and cookies policies.

2\. Performance data  
This lets us track how long it takes users to load each page, what pages we can cache.

3\. Embedded video (YouTube)  
We know that many of you love films, so the site may make use of clips on YouTube. YouTube sets its own cookies, and the [YouTube cookies policy](https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/types/) can be found here.

4\. Social media (Twitter)  
J.K. Rowling isn’t just a master of novel writing – she’s also pretty handy within the confines of 140 characters! The Company uses cookies to enable you to enjoy the social media features on the site. In order to host her tweets, we embed Twitter links. Twitter sets its own cookies, and [Twitter’s cookies policy](https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514) can be found here.

5\. Preferences  
The Company uses this type of cookie to ensure that it doesn’t show you things you’ve already seen before, like the cookie policy acceptance and the intro page. This means you get to spend more time with the content you love, and less time with the content you don’t.

6\. Session state  
Websites often collect information about how users interact with a website. This may include the pages that users visit most often, and whether users get error messages from certain pages. The Company uses these so-called “session state cookies” to help us improve the Company’s services, in order to improve our users’ browsing experience. Blocking or deleting these cookies will not render the site unusable.

By agreeing to the Company’s Terms and Conditions, you agree to the Company using the cookies and your information in these ways, but you can delete any of these cookies at any time if you wish.

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your web browser that allows you to refuse the setting of cookies, or you can modify your browser so that it notifies you when cookies are sent to it. The Help portion of your browser, most likely found on the toolbar, typically tells you how to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, how to have the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie, or how to disable cookies altogether. You can check whether these settings are currently enabled on your computer – or find out how to change your current settings – here:

Javascript: [www.enable-javascript.com](https://www.pottermore.com/about/www.enable-javascript.com)  
Cookies: [www.whatarecookies.com](https://www.pottermore.com/about/www.whatarecookies.com)

Alternatively, you may wish to visit the “manage cookies” section on [www.allaboutcookies.org](https://www.pottermore.com/about/www.allaboutcookies.org), which contains information on how to prevent cookies from being stored on your device as well as other helpful advice.

To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/>

Unless you do this, cookies will be issued when you use the site. If you do not accept cookies or decide to disable them, you will still be able to access and use the site, but you may lose some features and functionality.

You can find out more about cookies at [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

WHERE THE COMPANY STORES YOUR INFORMATION

The Company will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy & Cookies Policy.

All information you provide to the Company is stored on our secure servers. Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although the Company will do its best to protect your information, the Company cannot guarantee the security of the information you transmit to the site; any transmission is at your own risk.

Once the Company has received your information, the Company will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorised access, as required by applicable laws. In particular, we take steps to protect the security of your information with appropriate physical, technological and administrative measures. You accept the inherent risks of providing information and dealing online and will not hold us responsible for any breach of security that is due to circumstances beyond our reasonable control.

If you have any concerns about the security of your information or should you wish to access written information about our policies and practices regarding any of our authorised third-party service providers, please see the end of this Privacy & Cookies Policy for details of how to contact us.

USES MADE OF THE INFORMATION

The Company uses information held about you to ensure that content from the site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer, to provide you with the services outlined in this policy, and to understand how you use the site and how it is functioning so that the Company can maintain and improve the site.

The Company may use the information we collect to comply with law, to investigate a complaint made by another user or a potential breach of the site’s Terms and Conditions or to prevent and detect unlawful or criminal activity, fraud and misuse of, or damage to, the site or the products, content and services made available through it, and to take appropriate legal action against those responsible.

The Company may on occasion link or combine the information that we collect about you with information that we receive from other sources. The Company may combine this information with information you give to us and information the Company collects about you. (For example, we may decide to combine two or more databases into a single database of information.) We may use this information and the combined information for your and/or the Company’s benefit (for example, to allow the Company to provide a more seamless support and/or to provide you with better, personalised services and content).

DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION

The Company may disclose information that does not identify you personally including aggregated or de-identified data, in our discretion.

YOUR RIGHTS

The site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own terms and conditions and privacy & cookies policies and that the Company does not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

CONTACTING US

Please contact us to request the information that the Company holds on you,

If you would like to make a ‘data subject access request’ please be advised that any request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet the Company’s costs in providing you with details of the information held about you. Please address any requests to:

J.K. Rowling Website Limited  
c/o The Blair Partnership  
P.O. Box 7828  
London  
W1A 4GE

Please be advised that any personal information that you choose to provide us with when contacting us will be utilised in accordance with the Act (and any other applicable laws) and will be destroyed after the Company replies to any queries that you may raise.

CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY & COOKIES POLICY

Any changes the Company may make to this Privacy & Cookies Policy in the future will be posted on this page.

 _19th December 2016_
